Finding Aid for the Ethel Mary Ervin Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Ethel Mary Ervin Collection
1891-1903
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0568
.21 linear_feet
Biography/History
Ethel Mary Ervin, a native of Camden, Alabama, was born January 1, 1882. She graduated from George Peabody Normal College of the University of Nashville in 1901 and taught elementary school in Atmore, Alabama. After her 1904 marriage to Aubrey Jay Miller, they moved to Hood River, Oregon, in 1907. She died January 14, 1945.
This collection was assembled by and donated in 2004 by her nephew, Mark Ervin Campbell.
Scope and Contents
This .21 linear foot collection contains one three-ring binder with 27 pieces of original correspondence, with a transcription and photocopies. Also included are notes of recommendation, programs, and student cards. Ethel Mary “Dot” wrote most of the letters with the last letter being written by her younger brother, Albert Goode Ervin, Jr. “Budy” when he was 12 years old. “Lily” is the nickname of her mother, Elizabeth Ervin.
- Correspondence – (27)
  - from Dot to Ann, 1891
  - from Dot to Pa, December 4, 1898
  - from Glenn, October 2, 1899
  - from Dot to Lily, 1899
  - from Dot to Lily, October 17, 1899
  - from Dot to Lily, 1899
  - from Dot to Lily, October 17, 1899
  - from Dot to Lily, November 16, 1899
  - from Dot to Lily, November 20, 1899
  - from Dot to Lily, November 27, 1899
  - from Dot to Lily, February 8, 1900
  - from Dot to Lily, February 25, 1900
  - from Dot to Lily, April 1, 1900
  - from Dot to Lily, April 17, 1900
  - from Dot to Lily, May 11, 1900
  - from Dot to Lily, October 3, 1900
  - from Dot to Lily, October 8, 1900
  - from Dot to Lily, November 18, 1900
  - from Dot to Lily, November 25, 1900
  - from Dot to Lily, 1900
  - from Dot to Lily, February 15, 1901
  - from Dot to Lily, March 4, 1901
  - from Dot to Lily, March 31, 1901
  - from Dot to Lily, May 5, 1901
  - from Dot to Lily, 1901
  - from Dot to Lily, September 14, 1903
  - from Dot to Lily, 1903
  - from Dot to Lily, 1903
  - from Budy to Dot, October 4, 1903
- Programs – (2)
  - Peabody Normal College Mandolin, Banjo and Guitar Clubs Third Annual Concert, February 23, 1900
  - Students’ Christian Association Programme of Meetings and Bible Readings, March 1900
- Student Cards (3)
  - Summer School of the South
  - University of Tennessee, 1903
- Notes of Recommendation (9)
  - from Jas. A. Duncan, 1903
  - from Jno. B. Abernathy, 1903
  - W. Rose, 1901
  - from W. H. Payne, 1901
  - from H. A. Vance, 1901
  - Chas. B. Glenn, 1901
  - n.d. – Edwin Wexler Kennedy
  - A. P. Bourland, 1901
  - Julia A. Sears, 1901